Luiz Felipe Falcao

Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada

falcao.lfj@yahoo.com



linkedin.com/in/luizfelipejfalcao



(672) 513-2641



http://luizfelipefalcao.com

Summary

Bachelor of Computer Science and passionate about Javascript and its frameworks like ReactJS, I am a front-end web developer with 3+ years of experience that always seeks professional development using this stack.

I currently develop personal projects, in addition to looking for a job opportunity in order to improve my skills and learn more about the world of web development.

My skills include creating Single Page Applications (SPA's) and Landing Pages developing the concepts of componentization nailed by ReactJS. I also use the Firebase database and authenticator for excellent real-time performance, as well as Material-UI and Styled-Components for the stylization of my project.

Experience



Front-end Web Developer

Utopia Tech PTY LTD

Oct 2020 - Jul 2021 (10 months)

I worked with this great team as a front-end web developer, implementing pages for the main website that the company is developing and whose business solutions are the final product.

I implemented pages, features, filter categories and components using the following tools:

- Javascript as programming language;
- ReactJS and NextJs as frameworks;
- CSS and SASS for stylization;
- Consumption of API's;
- Jira for management and workflow;
- Use of Git and Gitlab for version control of our applications;

Stack: Javascript, ReactJS, NextJS, HTML5, CSS, SASS, Git, Gitlab, VSCode.



Software Engineer | Lua | IUP

Marinha do Brasil

Jan 2018 - Apr 2020 (2 years 4 months)

As a software developer using the Lua programming language and its libraries as IUP, I worked on the maintenance of the SJD (Didactic Games Simulator), maintaining the database and optimizing the simulator performance.

Stack: Lua, IUP, PostgreSQL



Brazilian Marine Corps - IT Support Technician

Marinha do Brasil

Jan 2011 - Jan 2018 (7 years 1 month)

As a support technician for the Marine Armored Battalion (Brazilian Navy), which had more than 70 workstations. I worked in several roles:

- Maintenance and optimization of intranet and internet services using SUSE Linux and Windows Server operating systems.
- Maintenance of workstations, installing and updating the applications used for the workflow;
- Data repository and storage of confidential documents;
- Configuration of several Brazilian Navy's systems, used by that battalion, such as: encrypted messaging systems, e-mail platforms, among others.
- Military technical training for the use of administrative systems.



Brazilian Marine Corps

Marinha do Brasil

Jan 2008 - Jan 2011 (3 years 1 month)

When I joined the Marine Corps of the Brazilian Navy, I served in the Marine Group of Ladário and operated in the most diverse exercises performed by that group.

Education



🕍 Centro Universitário UniCarioca

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 2013 - 2018

Licenses & Certifications

ReactJS do zero ao avançado na prática - React/Redux - 17,5 horas - Udemy UC-35bc6bc6-bfb9-48f9-a06a-d8fef70457b2/



Cambly Certificate of Accomplishment - 24 hours of English conversation practice with Cambly's native English teachers - Cambly Inc.

ff4cef1d

Skills

Front-end Development • Javascript • React.js • Computer Science • Web Development • Responsive Web Design • Software Development • HTML5 • CSS • Git

Honors & Awards



Amphibious Merit Medal - Brazilian Navy - Marines Corps

Medal of amphibious merit, honor for the services provided and missions accomplished.